<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OMS - Blog</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 21:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 21:24:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Come and sing with Ormskirk Music Society</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like singing…then why not &lt;em&gt;come and sing&lt;/em&gt; with Ormskirk Music Society?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday 9 September 2016 at 7.30pm, the choir of Ormskirk Music Society are holding a 
FREE “come and sing” event at Ormskirk School, Wigan Road, Ormskirk L39 2AT. 
Everyone is welcome, whether or not you have sung with a choir before. All we ask is that you enjoy singing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be learning two choral classics, Handel’s ‘Zadok the Priest’ and ‘The Rhythm of Life’ from the musical, &lt;em&gt;Sweet Charity&lt;/em&gt;. 
Full tuition, sheet music and refreshments will be provided. You can also meet existing members and find out more about the Society. 
Call 01925 221301 for more info. No need to book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in joining Ormskirk Music Society…why not get in touch or come along to a rehearsal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestra&lt;/strong&gt; - Thursdays at 7.45pm
email &lt;a href=&quot;clarebhamilton@hotmail.com&quot;&gt;clarebhamilton@hotmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or call 01925 221301&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choir&lt;/strong&gt; - Fridays at 7.30pm
email &lt;a href=&quot;omschoir.sec@gmail.com&quot;&gt;omschoir.sec@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or call 01695 624253&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/08/24/come-and-sing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/08/24/come-and-sing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>choir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Last Night of the Proms...concert report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh what a night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choir and orchestra sang and played their hearts out at this festival of music 
from England, Ireland, Scotland and Wales. Whether it was the orchestra belting out ‘Men of Harlech’ 
in the finale of Edward German’s &lt;em&gt;Welsh Rhapsody&lt;/em&gt; or the choir giving it their all in their set of 
Sea Shanties, everyone gave 100% and the audience loved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people move heaven and earth to make these concerts happen. Especial thanks go to 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rebeccamillsharp.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bec Mills&lt;/a&gt;, our harpist who stepped in at the very last minute 
and brought that magical extra something to the orchestral sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choral sound got a great boost when it was the audience’s turn to join in with the traditional Last Night 
numbers, ‘Land of Hope and Glory’ and ‘Jerusalem’. They also put in a highly musical and disciplined display of clapping 
during the ‘Sailor’s Hornpipe’ - well done audience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choir and orchestra and orchestra are now looking towards our next concert. For the orchestra, this will include a performance 
of Beethoven’s 7th Symphony, which is something lots of us have wanted to play for a long time. As always, both choir and orchestra 
are interested in 
recruiting new members so please do visit the rest of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ormskirkmusicsociety.org.uk&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to find out about our rehearsal 
times and our venue. Get in touch or, better still, come along to one of our rehearsals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 7 and 14 July, the orchestra will be holding open rehearsals to play through Beethoven’s 5th and Schumann’s 2nd 
Symphonies. This should be a really fun occasion and there will even be tea and cake at halftime! If you could drop an email to
&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; to let me know if you would like to come along, that would be great. Maybe see you there…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/concerts/2016/07/05/concert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/concerts/2016/07/05/concert.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>concerts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Last Night of the Proms...coming soon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The choir and orchestra are now well into their preparations for our Last Night of 
the Proms themed concert on &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/diary.html&quot;&gt;2 July 2016&lt;/a&gt;, subtitled ‘Music of the Four Countries’. 
This little extract comes from the 2015 Last Night and features the leader of the 
BBC Symphony Orchestra playing that famous solo from Sir Henry Wood’s &lt;em&gt;Fantasia on British Sea Songs&lt;/em&gt;, 
a.k.a. the Sailor’s Hornpipe. Just to get you in the mood!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a feast of music coming up from all around the Home Nations: a Welsh Rhapsody, an Irish 
Rhapsody, plus music from Scotland and of course England! It will all be rounded off with those Last 
Night staples, including Elgar’s ‘Pomp and Circumstance March No. 1’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, come along, sing along, and enjoy a great summer evening’s entertainment. For details of tickets 
and more, &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/diary.html&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 20:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/concerts/2016/05/23/last-night-of-the-proms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/concerts/2016/05/23/last-night-of-the-proms.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>concerts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Concert report - Spring orchestral concert</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;That concert was quite something!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of notes for everyone and a big thank you to Jim for keeping us all together 
throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off with Suk’s &lt;em&gt;Scherzo Fantastique&lt;/em&gt; which was no easy play but felt like something of a warm up 
in comparison with the challenges to come. A warm, flowing evocative piece in that fantastic, melodic Czech 
tradition, with a hint of mystery along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next came the mighty &lt;em&gt;Symphonic Dances&lt;/em&gt; by Rachmaninov. Rhythm, rhythm, rhythm - keep counting people!! - plus 
some typically Rachmaninov long melodies. I think we all felt quite energised by the end…and that was only the first half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half saw us perform excerpts from Prokofiev’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; Suites. We had worked hard on this for many months and 
that really paid off. This probably sounds very “down to earth” but I never get tired of playing the ‘Dance of the Knights’ (yes, I mean 
the music from the &lt;em&gt;Apprentice&lt;/em&gt;!!) To do this on Shakespeare’s 400th anniversary felt very meaningful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as giving heartfelt thanks to Jim, the orchestra is so grateful to the many friends and guests who joined us for the 
performance. Thanks are also due to the members of the choir who helped to make the concert possible with their 
fantastic contribution to the front of house effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking ahead now to our &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/diary.html&quot;&gt;“Last Night of the Proms”&lt;/a&gt; concert on 2 July 2016. 
Hope you can join us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/orchestra/2016/04/26/orchestra-concert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/orchestra/2016/04/26/orchestra-concert.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>orchestra</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Concert report - the Choir of Ormskirk Music Society...and guests</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What an enjoyable evening we had last night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks must go first and foremost to Phil and the choir for all their hard 
work. Another big thank you to Phil in his capacity as tenor soloist, giving 
us great performances of Puccini and Gilbert and Sullivan. We also had the privilege 
to hear soprano, Rochelle Hart, singing arias from &lt;em&gt;Tosca&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Don Giovanni&lt;/em&gt;, and the ‘Habenera’ 
from &lt;em&gt;Carmen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Willow Brass also put in some lovely performances, including a Quintet by Victor Ewald. This was 
not a piece I had come across before and it was nice to hear it. Thanks must also go to piano accompanist, 
Simon Passmore, and organist, Tom Cooper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed very fitting that the concert ended on a high with the audience on its feet, listening to the 
mighty Hallelujah Chorus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done everyone!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/04/10/choir-concert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/04/10/choir-concert.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>choir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rachmaninov: learning from the best...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of really great resources online for classical musicians.
None of them is perhaps as valuable as an extra hour of practice every 
week, but nevertheless, there is some good stuff out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this very timely and relevant resource a couple of days ago. The 
Sydney Symphony Orchestra has quite an active online presence and as part of this 
they have posted a whole series of masterclasses on YouTube. I was particularly
interested in this video. It shows 
the concertmaster of the orchestra (we would call him the leader of the orchestra in the UK) 
giving a young violinist some constructive criticism about his performance of 
a section from the first movement of Rachmaninov’s Symphonic Dances, which the 
&lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/orchestra.html&quot;&gt;orchestra of Ormskirk Music Society&lt;/a&gt; is playing 
in our &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/diary.html&quot;&gt;concert&lt;/a&gt; on 23 April 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The section in question is a very magical moment in the piece and is definitely 
one of those passages we string players look forward to. Lots of passion, 
maximum vibrato, Rachmaninov at his passionate best. If you watch the video you 
will learn that the section was actually bowed and edited at Rachmaninov’s 
request by the great &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fritz_Kreisler&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fritz Kreisler&lt;/a&gt;. 
There’s some star quality for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had watched the video, I picked up my violin and it really did sound 
better than it did before. Let’s hope we can take some inspiration from 
Maestro Kreisler right here in West Lancashire.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/orchestra/2016/03/08/masterclass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/orchestra/2016/03/08/masterclass.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>orchestra</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accompanist needed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/choir.html&quot;&gt;choir&lt;/a&gt; of Ormskirk Music Society is looking for an accompanist to assist 
the choral director with term time rehearsals (Fridays 7.30pm - 9.30pm) 
and concerts (usually four per year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for someone who can play piano to a reasonable standard 
and has good sight-reading skills. Previous experience of 
accompanying vocal groups would be great but is not essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ormskirk is approximately 13 miles northeast of Liverpool and 
has good rail, road and bus links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A modest “honorarium” plus 
travelling expenses will be paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact Diane Meredith on
&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#115;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;
or 01695 624253 if you would like more information about this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 20:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/02/08/accompanist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/choir/2016/02/08/accompanist.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>choir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rehearsals underway</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So the orchestra is practising hard for the &lt;a href=&quot;/oms-website/public_html/diary.html&quot;&gt;Spring concert on 23 April 2016&lt;/a&gt;. 
We might not be ready to trade venues with the Vienna Philharmonic
yet but things are definitely starting to take shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a string sectional rehearsal on tomorrow (Thursday 4 February) where we will
do some work on the Rachmaninov &lt;em&gt;Symphonic Dances&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a tough play but as always with Rachmaninov, the rewards are enormous.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/rehearsals/2016/02/03/test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/rehearsals/2016/02/03/test.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rehearsals</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to the new OMS website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the new Ormskirk Music Society website. We hope you enjoy exploring our site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any comments or suggestions please contact our web team on &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#098;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 21:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/website/2016/01/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://clarebhamilton.github.io/oms-website/public_html/blog/website/2016/01/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>website</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
